[Sharp Blade in the Snow]
[نصل حاد في الثلج]
[Episode 4] Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
[الحلقة 4] دعم الإدارة. شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
It's cold.
انها بارده.
Standing barefoot on the floor
الوقوف حافياً على الأرض
will make you catch a chill.
سيجعلك تشعر بقشعريرة.
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك،
Princess Royal heard that your old illness has returned
سمعت الأميرة الملكية أن مرضك القديم قد عاد
and sent some medicine.
وأرسل بعض الأدوية.
I'll do it.
سأفعل ذلك.
This medicine is poisoned.
هذا الدواء ملوث.
I want to see
أريد أن أرى
if you'll really drink this bowl of poison.
إذا كنت ستشرب حقاً هذا الوعاء من السم.
The Princess Royal certainly chose well— you really know how to serve.
لقد أحسنت الأميرة الملكية الاختيار بالتأكيد - أنتِ حقاً تعرفين كيف تقدمين الطعام.
You've caused serious trouble.
لقد تسببت في مشكلة خطيرة.
Tell me,
أخبرني،
how should I punish you?
كيف أعاقبك؟
Punishing me is nothing.
معاقبتي لا شيء.
But if you catch a chill, that would be serious.
لكن إذا أصبت بنزلة برد، فسيكون الأمر خطيراً.
Why not
ولم لا
let me help you change your clothes?
هل تسمح لي بمساعدتك في تغيير ملابسك؟
Now you're really in trouble.
أنت الآن في ورطة حقيقية.
Your Majesty, are you painting red plum blossoms?
جلالتك، هل ترسم أزهار البرقوق الحمراء؟
Do you like plum blossoms, Your Majesty?
هل تحب أزهار البرقوق يا صاحب الجلالة؟
Yes.
نعم.
My mother loved plum blossoms—
كانت والدتي تحب أزهار البرقوق—
blooming in the cold, proud and unyielding,
تزهر في البرد، فخورة لا تلين،
crimson like blood.
قرمزي اللون كالدم.
How captivating they are.
كم هم آسرون!
More captivating
أكثر جاذبية
than me?
أكثر مني؟
Serve me
اخدمني
well,
حسنًا،
just like they do.
تماماً كما يفعلون.
Who knows—I might even grant you the title of High Consort.
من يدري، ربما أمنحكِ لقب القرينة العليا.
We
نحن
have plenty of time ahead of us.
أمامنا وقت طويل.
The Queen truly favors Yun Zhan.
الملكة تُفضّل يون زان حقاً.
The affection in her eyes is almost impossible to hide.
من المستحيل تقريباً إخفاء المودة التي تظهر في عينيها .
With looks like Yun Zhan's,
بمظهر يشبه يون زان،
forget the Queen—
انسَ أمر الملكة—
even you and I couldn't help being tempted.
حتى أنا وأنت لم نستطع مقاومة الإغراء.
Mr. Bai.
السيد باي.
Go.
يذهب.
Yun Zhan,
يون زان,
you'd better behave yourself.
من الأفضل أن تتصرف بشكل لائق.
Such audacity.
يا لها من جرأة!
The Queen's status is supremely noble.
مكانة الملكة نبيلة للغاية.
She is no pleasure-seeking noblewoman
إنها ليست سيدة نبيلة تسعى وراء المتعة
from the Slave House.
من بيت العبيد.
Know your place!
اعرف مكانتك!
We've always been intense,
لطالما كنا متحمسين،
Mr. Bai.
السيد باي.
Who do you think you are?
من تظن نفسك؟
You...
أنت...
I may be nothing special—
قد لا أكون شيئاً مميزاً.
just a bit spoiled by the Queen's favor.
لقد أفسدتني الملكة قليلاً.
I am the Prime Minister's only son,
أنا الابن الوحيد لرئيس الوزراء،
born of a noble house.
ولد من عائلة نبيلة.
Defying me is an act of insubordination.
إن تحدي أوامري هو عمل من أعمال العصيان.
If I wished,
لو أردت،
I could take your life at any moment.
بإمكاني أن أنهي حياتك في أي لحظة.
Then the Queen
ثم الملكة
would be heartbroken.
سيكون قلبي محطماً.
[Lu Ran, Medical Envoy of Mocheng]
[لو ران، المبعوث الطبي لموتشنغ]
I'm Lu Ran, death guard of Dongli,
أنا لو ران، حارس الموت في دونغلي،
pay my respects to Your Highness.
أبلغ سموكم احترامي.
Rise quickly.
انهض بسرعة.
You have fallen into exile, hiding in the martial world
لقد وقعت في المنفى، مختبئًا في عالم الحرب.
as "Stone Yama the Rogue,"
بصفته "ستون ياما المارق"،
and have suffered greatly,
وقد عانوا معاناة شديدة،
yet still had to
ومع ذلك كان لا يزال يتعين عليه
endure humiliation at Bai Yu's hands.
تحمل الإذلال على يد باي يو.
If he had not wounded me,
لو لم يكن قد جرحني،
how could I have ever met you?
كيف لي أن ألتقي بك؟
General Lu,
الجنرال لو،
since the fall of Dongli,
منذ سقوط دونغلي،
you have remained in the deep palace of Mocheng.
لقد بقيت في أعماق قصر موتشينغ.
It is you who have been wronged.
أنت من ظُلِم.
For Dongli,
بالنسبة لدونجلي،
I will serve until death.
سأخدم حتى الموت.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
now that you've successfully entered the palace,
الآن وقد دخلت القصر بنجاح،
what is our next move?
ما هي خطوتنا التالية؟
Wait.
انتظر.
Wait?
انتظر؟
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
why change the plan?
لماذا تغيير الخطة؟
Why not kill her now?
لماذا لا تقتلها الآن؟
I've learned
لقد تعلمت
that Feng Li possesses the formula
أن فنغ لي يمتلك الصيغة
for Feng Condensation Incense,
لبخور فنغ المكثف،
which can control men's minds.
والتي يمكنها السيطرة على عقول الرجال.
In Mocheng,
في موتشنغ،
where women rule,
حيث تحكم النساء،
this evil incense has long harmed the people.
لقد ألحق هذا البخور الشرير الضرر بالناس منذ زمن طويل.
We must wait for the right moment.
علينا أن ننتظر اللحظة المناسبة.
I will reclaim Dongli
سأستعيد دونغلي
and make Mocheng pay in blood.
وأجعل موتشينغ يدفع الثمن بالدم.
I will also obtain the formula for the evil incense
سأحصل أيضاً على تركيبة البخور الشرير
and wipe out both the Demon Lord and that incense
واقضِ على سيد الشياطين وعلى ذلك البخور
once and for all.
مرة واحدة وإلى الأبد.
[All Is for Benevolence]
[كل شيء من أجل الإحسان]
Lord Meng Wu of Mocheng
اللورد منغ وو من موتشنغ
instructed me
أرشدني
to add a small dose of poison
لإضافة جرعة صغيرة من السم
to the Queen's medicinal decoction every day.
إلى مغلي الملكة الطبي كل يوم.
They scheme and vie against each other,
إنهم يتآمرون ويتنافسون ضد بعضهم البعض،
unaware that
غير مدرك أن
you are the ultimate beneficiary
أنت المستفيد النهائي
waiting in the wings.
ينتظر دوره.
The Demon Lord is meticulous
سيد الشياطين دقيق للغاية
and difficult to win over.
ومن الصعب كسب تأييده.
Perhaps this is worth a try.
ربما يستحق الأمر المحاولة.
You're here?
أنت هنا؟
Your Majesty, how did you know it was me?
يا صاحب الجلالة، كيف عرفت أنني أنا؟
Everyone carries a distinct scent—
لكل شخص رائحة مميزة.
especially you.
وخاصة أنت.
Don't be nervous.
لا تكن عصبيا.
Just acupressure,
مجرد علاج بالضغط على نقاط معينة،
to dispel dampness and cool your system.
للتخلص من الرطوبة وتبريد النظام.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك،
your inner heat runs high.
ترتفع حرارة جسمك الداخلية.
While the tonic is strengthening,
بينما يعمل المنشط على تقوية الجسم،
too much of it
الكثير منه
can aggravate your inner heat.
قد يؤدي ذلك إلى زيادة حرارة جسمك الداخلية.
My temper has been raging lately.
لقد اشتد غضبي مؤخراً.
Perhaps killing a few would serve to quell my temper.
ربما قتل بعض الأشخاص سيساعد في تهدئة غضبي.
That medicine is poisoned.
هذا الدواء مسموم.
Really?
حقًا؟
How could that be?
كيف يمكن أن يكون ذلك؟
Who wants to harm me?
من يريد أن يؤذيني؟
If you wish to soothe your temper,
إذا كنت ترغب في تهدئة أعصابك،
perhaps
ربما
you'll allow me to try.
ستسمح لي بالمحاولة.
Try.
يحاول.
Your Majesty, then
جلالتك إذن
you have to endure a bit.
عليك أن تتحمل قليلاً.
You want me to...
تريدني أن...
What?
ماذا؟
Don't you like it, Your Majesty?
ألا يعجبك ذلك يا جلالة الملك؟
I just think
أعتقد فقط
it lacks intensity.
يفتقر إلى الحماس.
Father!
أب!
Run!
يجري!
-Your Highness, go! -Go!
- يا صاحب السمو، انطلق! - انطلق!
Don't be afraid, I'm here.
لا تخف، أنا هنا.
Sit here.
اجلس هنا.
Prime Minister Yun,
رئيس الوزراء يون،
weren't Dongli and Mocheng
لم تكن Dongli وMocheng
here to sign an alliance?
هل أنت هنا لتوقيع تحالف؟
Why are they trying to kill us?
لماذا يحاولون قتلنا؟
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
we've fallen into Mocheng's trap.
لقد وقعنا في فخ Mocheng.
They never meant to form an alliance.
لم يكن قصدهم أبدًا تشكيل تحالف.
This was a ruse to lure us out and silence us,
كانت هذه حيلة لاستدراجنا وإسكاتنا،
to kill both you and His Majesty.
لقتلك أنت وجلالته.
I'll fight them to the death.
سأقاتلهم حتى الموت.
Your Highness, you must not!
يا صاحب السمو، لا يجوز لك ذلك!
Change clothes.
غيّر ملابسك.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
from now on,
من الآن فصاعدًا،
you are my son Yun Zhan.
أنت ابني يون زان.
No.
لا.
How could I
كيف لي أن أفعل ذلك؟
trade someone else's life
استبدل حياة شخص آخر
for my own?
من أجلي؟
Cang Lin,
كانج لين,
I was never meant to live long.
لم يكن مقدراً لي أن أعيش طويلاً.
Only if you survive
فقط إذا نجوت
will Dongli have a future.
هل سيكون لدونغلي مستقبل؟
Remember this—
تذكر هذا—
no matter what happens,
بغض النظر عما يحدث،
you must live on
يجب أن تعيش
and restore Dongli.
وإعادة دونغلي.
Crown Prince Cang Lin,
ولي العهد كانغ لين،
I require you to swear an oath.
أطلب منك أن تقسم يميناً.
I swear in the name of the Dongli royal house:
أقسم باسم العائلة المالكة دونغلي:
this debt of blood
دين الدم هذا
will one day be repaid
سيتم سدادها يوماً ما
by Mocheng in kind.
من موشينغ عيناً.
No.
لا.
I haven't obtained world-ruining incense formula yet.
لم أحصل بعد على تركيبة البخور التي ستدمر العالم.
She cannot die.
لا يمكنها أن تموت.
Why did you stop?
لماذا توقفت؟
Those pressure points are enough.
نقاط الضغط تلك كافية.
Going any further
المضي قدماً
might harm you.
قد يضرك ذلك.
It does feel much better now.
أشعر بتحسن كبير الآن.